Resume

Eddie Wu

1. Profile.

Chinese Name: Wu Jianfeng

Gender: Male
Degree: Bachelor

Working Experience: 5⁺ years in J2EE Development (10 years total)

Mobile Phone: 13661788694

Email: ueddieu@yahoo.com.cn

2. Skills Summary.

I have more than five years working experience in J2EE application development. With the solid knowledge of J2EE platform and Oracle database, I am good at performance tuning of enterprise application. Besides J2EE platform and Oracle database, I also self studied a lot about Linux Kernel, Algorithm and Data Structure, Computer Architecture, etc. because I am interested on those topics.

2.1. Algorithm and Data Structure

I keep self-studying algorithm and data structure even though it is not directly used in my daily work. From "Introduction to Algorithm" to "The Art of Computer Programming", I keep reading them again and again. I not only read them, but also apply the theory in practice; last week I just resolved one problem—"Search Engine Arrangement Optimization" from Google Code Jam with Greedy algorithm.

2.2. Programming Language(C/C++/Java) and OOD

I have more than five years' Java programming experience. To study the kernel implementation and Hot Spot JVM implementation, I also self-studied a lot about C and C++. Now I can read the Linux Kernel source code to understand how it works without any difficulty.

I have good understanding of classic GOF Design Patterns and J2EE patterns. Design Pattern is a live example of how to apply the OOD principle to address the design problem. Mastering the design pattern is also an improvement of my understanding of Object Oriented Design.

2.3. Unix/Linux

I am interested in Unix Operating System design and implementation. I have read many books about Unix/Linux, including "Linux Kernel Scenario Analysis", "Understanding the Linux Kernel", "Linux Kernel Development". From 2007, I start to read the Linux source code. Now I am quite clear about how the Linux kernel is implemented, especially the implementation of Memory Management System.

2.4. Oracle Database.

I have systematically studied the Oracle database and get OCP on 2006. I know the Oracle Architecture and know how the SQL statement is executed internally. With those knowledge, I have succeeded in performance tuning several large-scale WEB applications.

2.5. English

I not only can read and write technical document fluently in English, but also can communicate with native speaker face to face or through conference call.

In order to co-develop a project on site, I have ever been to San Francisco for one month on March of 2007.

2.6 Certificates.

I do not think the Certificate is a good measure one's capability, but I do think pursuing a certificate can help me learn the knowledge systematically and quickly. Here is the certificate I have ever pursued successfully.

Date	Certificate Name	Score	Serial Number
2006/07	Oracle DBA Professional	92, 98, 87, 91	
2004/10	IBM Certified Solution Developer	72	
	—WebSphere Studio, V5.0		
2004/09	SCJP (Sun Certified Java Programmer)	98	409182
2003/01	Certified Advanced Programmer	53 + 61	02-81-13-021
2002/03	Certified Programmer	70 + 59	0121400294

3. Work Experience

I started my first full-time IT job from March 15, 2004, till now I have more than five years experience on J2EE platform. Before that, I have worked in Pharmaceutical industry for almost 5 years; during that period, I self-studied computer science and apply the technology I learned in part-time project.

3.1. Shanghai Bleum Inc. (October 2004 - Now)

I have worked in Bleum for more than 4 years. I joined Bleum as a software engineer, and gradually grow up to senior software engineer, technical leader, architect, and project leader.

3.1.1. Project Leader (May 2008 – Now)

I start to take the full responsibility of a project, which is a public website, provide service for potential credit card holder — high school students or college students.

During the past year, I lead the team deliver the projects on time and with high quality; one of the project is customer certified zero-defect project.

We encountered performance issue in the production environment, and we successfully addressed it from two aspects; one is to tune the SQL statement to ensure the scalability of application, and another one is to optimize the front end performance by adopting the best practices published by Yahoo.

Since the whole team are still young, I spend many effort to train them on technical skills, such as database tuning, and communication skills, such as how to raise question and write email to customer.

3.1.2. Architect (October 2007 – May 2008)

As an architect, I start oversight all the projects in the ODC(Offshore Development Center). My major duty include training, evaluation, technical interview, trouble-shooting, technical improvement, and development process improvement.

During this period, I have introduced GlassFish application server into one project, which supports hot deployment and improve the developer's productivity. (In that project, Tomcat's hot deployment feature does not work properly because of some Axis related code.)

In another project, we have many duplicate environment related Spring configuration file, one for each environment, it is hard to maintain. I suggest customer to use template Spring configuration file to keep all the configuration in one file. Customer appreciated it and adopted in the project.

3.1.3. Technical Leader(October 2006 – October 2007)

One of project during this period is to add new feature — PDF printing for a WEB site, and to change the looking and feel by using more pop up window. The PDF printing is a big challenge for us until we found a tool called PD4ML, which supports the conversion from dynamic JSP content to PDF. We also verified that it can works well in the load of about twenty concurrent users.

As the technical leader of this project. My major achievement is the PDF printing solution based on PD4ML, which is highly appreciated by customer.

Another project during this period is to migrate three back end procedures written in Toplink, those procedure are scheduled to synchronize data between different databases everyday. We are required to re-implement the existing procedure and improve the performance.

For the convenience of performance tuning, we decide to access database through JDBC. After we finish the implementation, we measure the performance with JProfiler and identify the bottle neck. Actually, most of time are spend in data access layer, we tune the SQL statement and finally improved the performance to be two times better than before (The back end procedure can finish in half an hour instead of one hour).

As the technical leader of this project. My major responsibility is designing and performance tuning.

3.1.4. Senior Software Engineer (October 2005 – October 2006)

This project is to optimize performance of an existing application, since customer is not satisfied with the performance of the existing system. We got following lessons and experience about application performance tuning.

First, we should consider performance requirement and perform load test in construction phase; Second, the load test environment should be as close to real production environment as possible, load test environment should include same amount of data and same amount of concurrent user in database. Third, Hibernate may generate some unnecessary table joins, the solution is to use native SQL instead of HQL in such case. Last but not the least, all the SQL Statement, including the SQL statement generated by Hibernate, should be reviewed to decide whether existing index is enough or not and what new index we need to add.

I am the major developer of this project. I not only improved the performance of the application (several SQL query speeds up more than ten times after tuning), but also gain a lot of hands on experience on Oracle database.

3.1.5. Software Engineer (December, 2004 - October, 2005)

The architecture of this project is a little special, the business layer is located in Tibco Bizwork server, and Application server basically is a client of the web service published by Tibco Bizwork. The major challenge in this project is to resolve the issues in using Axis, for example, memory leak issue. We also developed a mock mechanism to develop and test WEB layer when the business layer is not ready. (Business layer is joint-developed simultaneously by another two teams, one is in America and the other is in Singapore.)

I researched on Axis and give training about Axis to team members in the design phase.

3.2. Shanghai Zhongxin Development Inc. (March 2004 – December 2004)

The application is deployed on Oracle 9i Application Server in the local area net. It is used to manage all kind of registry and approve of Shanghai Production Security Administration Bureau. The Project achieved success in the use of Struts Framework, which saves us a lot of work. I am in charge of implementing the Business Flow module and System Manage module.

My responsibility includes Designing, Coding, Unit/Integration testing of related module.

3.3. Shanghai Zhongxi Pharmaceutical Inc. (May 2001 – March 2004)

In this period, I worked in Marketing Department providing academic support for new drugs. In my non-working time, I continually learning Java programming language and other Computer Science subject, and got the certificate of Programmer and Advanced Programmer. Then I started to be involved in the following IT projects in my leisure time.

3.3.1. Chinese Chess Game On Internet (September 2003 – November 2003).

In this project, we need to develop a Chinese Chess Game application of Server/Client architecture. Its main features include negotiating the regulation, playing between a pairs of player through internet, watching other player's game, counting of time, and requesting to regret the step taken. The player's information is stored in the databases, and every game can been scored automatically by application.

I am in charge of the design and implementation of the client side, implementation of chess rule in the Server side. It took me a lot of time to develop the GUI in client side and to integrate it with the server side.

3.3.2. Go Game (Weiqi) Applet (May 2002 - August 2002).

As an ancient Chinese game, Go is very complex. This program can help the GO players to improve their skills especially skills in "making live" in the board. With the correct strategy stored in the data file, the applet, which is downloaded from Internet, can fight against the player, and beat him unless the player has master the skills. This applet improved the interactivity in the teaching and learning of Go related skill.

I am in charge of design and implementation of the program by myself. I also build a simple temporary WEB site to test the Applet.

3.4. Suzhou NO.2 Pharmaceutical Factory (July 1999 – May 2001)

During this period, I worked in R&D department and took part in the developing of a new chemical drug – Paroxtine. My major responsibility includes chemical synthesis and chemical analysis. At the same time, I start to self-study Java programming language and other Computer Science subject.

4. Education and Training

1994-1999 Shenyang Pharmaceutical University Pharmacy English (5 years)